Guide to the Rutherfurd Family Papers 1721-1879 MS 532
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series 10: Other Persons, 1680-1879 and Undated (Box 11, Box 14, Box 20, Box 12, Box 13)
  The series also includes accounts, bills, receipts, legal papers, and surveys of persons not related to the Rutherfurd family, and of unknown persons. For the most part, all such material is interfiled regardless of its original creator or possessor. Legal Papers and Accounts, Bills, Receipts are arranged chronologically. Surveys are arranged alphabetically by the surname of the owner of the tract surveyed.
  David Provoost, because of the volume of material pertaining to him, is the only individual person in the series to be assigned a folder of Accounts, Bills, Receipts. Wills and inventories of estates are also foldered according to the names of the testators.
  Note that two items from the Other Persons series are in Box 20. One is labelled Other Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts -- Account Book of Unidentified Person. The other is labelled Surveys - A Record of Surveys of the Ramopock Tract in Bergen County in the Province of New-Jersey.
  - Other Persons -- William Abbot -- Letters Received, 1794-1804 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Other Persons -- Gen. Alexander Adamson -- Letters Received, 1838-1839 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Other Persons -- William Alexander (of Edinburgh) -- Letters Received, 1743-1746 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Other Persons -- Sir Edmund Antrobus -- Letters Received, 1833, 1836-1837 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Other Persons -- William Bard -- Letters Received, 1834, 1836 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Other Persons -- Baring Bros. & Co. -- Letters Received, 1813 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Other Persons -- R. Boggs -- Letters Received, 1807 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Other Persons -- Daniel Brent -- Letters Received, 1837 and Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Other Persons -- Duncan Brown -- Letters Received, 1750 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Other Persons -- Gen. [...] Clarkson -- Letters Received, 1803 (Bin 11, Folder 19)
  - Other Persons -- Lemuel Cobb -- Letters Received, 1795-1805 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Other Persons -- R. Cocks -- Letters Received, 1839 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Other Persons -- Cadwallader Colden -- Letters Received, 1741, 1749-1750 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Other Persons -- Thos. Coults & Co. -- Letters Received, 1814, 1830-1838 and Undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Other Persons -- John Cutter -- Letters Received, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Other Persons -- Farner & Co. -- Letters Received, 1839 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Other Persons -- Gen. [...] Hamilton -- Letters Received, 1821 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons -- James A. Hamilton -- Letters Received, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Other Persons -- George Harrison -- Letters Received, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Other Persons -- James Jauncey -- Letters Received, 1835 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Other Persons -- Peter Augustus Jay -- Letters Received, 1831 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Other Persons -- Isaac A. Johnson -- Letters Received, 1833 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Other Persons -- Philip Kearny -- Letters Received, 1838 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Other Persons -- John Kirkbride -- Letters Received, 1816 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Other Persons -- Benjamin Kissam -- Letters Received, 1765 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Other Persons -- Peter van Brugh Livingston -- Letters Received, 1755 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Other Persons -- Robert Livingston -- Letters Received, 1756 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Other Persons -- William Lunsden -- Letters Received, 1734-1735, 1747 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Other Persons -- Edward Marjoribanks (et al.) -- Letters Received, 1808, 1838-1839 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Other Persons -- Samuel Mitchelson -- Letters Received, 1772 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Other Persons -- James Morrell -- Letters Received, 1748-1750 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Other Persons -- James Morris -- Letters Received, 1796, 1800-1804 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Other Persons -- [...] Parkinson -- Letters Received, 1839 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Other Persons -- Benjamin Pitney -- Letters Received, 1800 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Other Persons -- Frederick [Preine] -- Letters Received, 1835 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Other Persons -- Archibald Russell -- Letters Received, 1839-1844 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Other Persons -- Alexander Rutherfurd, Lord Advocate of Scotland -- Letters Received, 1839 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Other Persons -- John Shoolbred -- Letters Received, 1788 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Other Persons -- John Smyth -- Letters Received, 1774 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Other Persons -- James Stephens -- Letters Received, 1726 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Other Persons -- Richard Stockton -- Letters Received, 1807 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Other Persons -- Herman Thorn -- Letters Received, 1833 and Undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Other Persons -- [...] Van Arsdale -- Letters Received, 1826 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Other Persons -- Elias Van Arsdale -- Letters Received, 1832 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Other Persons -- William Watson -- Letters Received, 1747-1753 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Other Persons -- George Willcocks -- Letters Received, 1720 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Other Persons -- William Wilson -- Letters Received, 1799, 1803-1804 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Other Persons -- John Budd -- Will, 1749 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Other Persons -- John J. Christie -- Will, 1818 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Other Persons -- Robert Hunter -- Will, 1718 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Other Persons -- David Provoost -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1701 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Other Persons -- David Provoost -- Inventory of Estate, 1701 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons -- Arent Sonmans -- Abstract of [Right in Propriety], 1738 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Other Persons -- John Spratt -- Inventory of Estate, 1697 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Other Persons -- Correspondence, Recipients Unknown, 1747-1874 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Other Persons -- Legal Papers, 1680-1737 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Other Persons -- Legal Papers, 1740-1764 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Other Persons -- Legal Papers, 1748-1853 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Other Persons -- Surveys -- A-O (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons -- Surveys -- P-Z (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Other Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1753-1879 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified Persons -- Memoranda (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Surveys -- Unidentified Tracts & Multiple Owners (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Surveys -- Maps (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Surveys -- A Record of the Surveys of the Ramopock Tract in Bergen County in the Province of New-Jersey (envelope), 1767 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts -- Account Book of Unidentified Person(envelope), 1803-1818 (Bin 20, Folder 3)
- Series 11: Court Papers, 1704-1832 and Undated (Box 20, Box 15)
  This series consists of papers relating to court cases adjudicated in New York and New Jersey in the 18th and 19th centuries. The cases are arranged alphabetically by the surname of the plaintiff. In those cases in which there was more than one plaintiff, the surname of the first named plaintiff is used. In two of the cases, members of the Rutherfurd family were defendants, and in one, John Stark Robertson appears to have been the defendant. Note that one item from this series, labelled Court papers -- Answer of Walter & CatherineRutherfurd -- Unidentified Suit is in Box 20, with other oversize material and volumes. For a list of the cases, consult the container list.
  - Court Papers -- Chalmers et al. vs. Clintock et al., 1840 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers -- Samuel & Meirs Fisher vs. Walter Rutherfurd, Undated (Bin 15, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers -- Hunt vs. Stirling et al., 1767 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers -- Jackson ex Dem. Halsey vs. Vail, 1740 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers -- Medina vs. Het, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers -- Ormstein vs. Sonmans, 1704 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers -- Pinhorn vs. van Buskirk, 1731 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers -- Provoost vs. DePeyster, 1704 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers -- John Stark Robison [sic] vs. James Scott Smith, 1799 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers -- Eliza Smith et al. vs. John Rutherfurd et al. (1 of 2), 1832 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Court Papers -- Eliza Smith et al. vs. John Rutherfurd et al. (2 of 2), 1832 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers -- Deposition of Robert Emleyin in Unidentified Proceeding, 1800 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Court Papers -- Deposition of Thomas Gordon in Unidentified Proceeding, 1720 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Court Papers -- State of Case & Opinion re Unidentified Proceeding, 1772 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Court Papers -- Answer of Walter & Catherine Rutherfurd -- Unidentified Suit, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Series 12: New Jersey Proprietors, 1723-1771 (Box 16)
  This series consists of assorted material having to do with or created on behalf of the Proprietors of the Eastern or Western Divisions of New Jersey.
  - New Jersey Proprietors -- Eastern Division -- Minutes & Resolutions, 1723-1793 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey Proprietors -- Eastern Division -- Warrants to Survey, 1749-1771 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey Proprietors -- Eastern Division -- Advertisement, 1743 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey Proprietors -- Western Division -- Resolutions, 1771 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Colony/State of New York -- Petition to Gov. Montgomerie, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Colony/State of New York -- Land Patents, 1688, 1750 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - NewJersey/New York Boundary -- Certificate of Survey, 1774 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Remaining Series, [1707]-1803 and Undated (Box 16)
  The remaining series in the collection consist of small amounts of material having to do with specific institutions or geographical locations. Which family members (if any) these items pertain to, is not clear.
  - Colony/State of Connecticut -- Grant of Land for New Fairfield, [1707] (Bin 16, Folder 8)
  - Presbytery of Albany -- Minutes & Resolutions, 1803 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Schedule of Post Days at New York, 1793 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Fragments, Scrap & Wrappings (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Fragments, Scrap & Wrappings (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Oversize Legal Documents on Parchment (Box 19, Box 17, Box 18)
  - Oversize Legal Documents on Parchment (material is not foldered) (Box 17)
  - Oversize Legal Documents on Parchment (material is not foldered) (Box 18)
  - Oversize Legal Documents on Parchment (material is not foldered) (Box 19)